Guide to the Heinz Eulau Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-55
  - The Behavioral Movement in Political Science: A Personal Document, 1968 Spr. (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Tradition and Innovation: On the Tension between Ancient and Modern Ways in the Study of Politics, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Changing Views of Representation, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Antioch Review, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Religion and Power, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Wilsonian Idealist: Walter Lippmann Goes to War, 1954 Spr. (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Mover and Shaker: Walter Lippmann as a Young Man, 1951 Fall (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Antioch Review, 1951 Spr. (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - An Expert Speaks His Mind, undated (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - The Nation: Voices Without Smiles, What the Telephone Workers Really Want, 17262 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - The Inter-American, 1944 Mar. (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Theories of Federalism under the Holy Roman Empire, 1941 Aug. (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Man Against Himself: Walter Lippmann's Years of Doubt, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Books, Some Recent Pan Americana, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - The Reader Writes, Herbert Croly's Promise, undated (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Early Theories of Parliamentarism, 1942 Feb. (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - Antioch Review, 1956 Fall (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Germany: Economic and Labour Conditions under Facism, Review, 1945 Sum. (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - The Inter-American Quarterly, 1941 Oct. (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - The Public Opinion Quarterly, 1947 Sum. (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - The Depersonalization of the Concept of Sovereignty, 1942 Feb. (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Six Graet Newspapers of South America, 1942 Sep. (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Assorted floppy disks: Acadbio, etc., undated (Box 20, Folder 56)
  - Academic Culture MSS (1/2), undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Academic Culture MSS (2/2), undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Newbook Outline/ Table of Contents, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - A Proper Study of Political Behavior, A Personal Pathways Perspective, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - New Book, Table of Contents, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Email Correspondence from Susan Zlomke, 2001 Mar. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - HE Curriculum Vitae/ Bibiography, 1991 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, Poli. Sci., 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Proofreading Symbols, Maps, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Behavioralism in American Political Science: Is Eulau on Target?, undated (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Notes on Intercommunication Among Political Behaviorists, 1954 Sep. 24 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Had The Nation, the New Republic, Common Sense, Partisan Review, etc., undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Letter to an Editor, to Harvard University Press, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - The Changing Moods of the Social Sciences, 1962 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Context for Treatment, 1986 Dec. 12 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Players: The Political Attitudes and Behaviors of American Political Scientists, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Syllabi, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Heinz Eulau Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Faculty Questionnaire, Heinz Eulau, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Assorted letters and emails, undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Heinz Eulau's Immigration from Germany, 1998 May 15 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Trip receipts, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - L'Affaire, undated (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Gabriel A. Almond, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Stor searches, undated (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - John Babich letter, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Assorted photographs, undated (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Finale, Some Last and First Words and Words In-Between on a Long-Dead Topic from the Punditry, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Tea List, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - ICPSR Representatives Convene in Ann Arbor, 2000 Win. (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - H. E. Curriclum Vitae, undated (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Public Affairs Report, 1989 Jan. (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Campus Report: Eulau to head NSF election studies, 1977 Oct. 12 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - HE Bibliography, 1941-1986 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - A66 Lindenberger, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - HE, undated (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - On Bias and Disclosure: A Personal Pathways Perspective in Legislative Research, undated (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - HE at New Republic, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Erik Austin, Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - A Disclosure as Prologue, undated (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - On Living and Doing History, 1996 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - The Concept of Policy Mood, 0 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Endowment Fund envelope, 1997 Sep. 24 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Matthews, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Role and Reference Group Behavior, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Various letters, undated (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Various articles, undated (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Interview by Dwaine Marvick, 1988 Jan. 28 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Politics, Policy and Psychology: The Heritage of Harold D. Lasswell, 2003 Jan. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Masters: Preface/Epilogue, General Overview, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Masters: Ch. 4, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - HE Texts, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Working Paper on Roger Masters' Model of Human Behavior as a Biological Phenomenon: The Issue of Reduction, 1991 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Bulletin: The American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1991 Oct. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Various letters, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Political Development and Political Evolution, 1988 Feb. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Politics and the Life Sciences, 1987 Feb. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Politics and the State, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Evolutionary Biology and Natural Justice: A New Version of an Old Fallacy, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Randomness and the Twentieth Century, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - World Politics, 1983 Jan. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Masters Own MSS, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Various handwritten notes, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Thought Notes on Masters, The Nature of Politics, 1989 Sep. 19 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Notes for Masters, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Masters, Ch. 1: "Animal Behavior and Human Altruism", 1989 Nov. 24 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Natural Right and History, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - The American Political Science Review, 1928 Feb. (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - The Nature of Politics, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Gruter Institute for Law and Behavioral Research, 1989 Sum. (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Gruter Institute for Law and Behavioral Research, 1990 Spr. (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Membership List of the Association for Politics and the Life Sciences, 1990 Jan. 1 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - A Biological Definition of Politics, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Homo Sapiens as the Political Animal, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Susan's Text, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
  - Original Notes, Finished, 1990 Jan. 24 (Box 22, Folder 29)
  - Fun, Fiobles, and Fumbles in Academia: Facts and Fables about the Culture of the Learned Life, 1996 Jul. 26 (Box 22, Folder 30)
  - Communism and the Abuse of Free Speech, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - The Bookshelf, An Expert Speaks His Mind, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Variety, The "Liberal" Fifth Column: A Discussion, 1946 Nov. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - The Behavioral Persuasion in Politics, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - The American Behavioral Scientist, 1961 May (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Antioch Review, 1948 Win. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Liberals and Conservatives, 1789-1951, 1951-1952 Win. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - We Note... What Kind of Responsibility for China?, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - ICPSR Bulletin, 1984 Jan. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Social Network Analysis and Political Behavior: A Feasibility Study, 1981 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Micro and Macro -- On Units and Levels of Analysis, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - The University of Iowa brochures, undated (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Social Science History, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Circles Around the Circle: A Preliminary Report on a Network, Approach to Representation at the Local Level, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - An Assessment of Party and Incumbent Accountability in Midterm Congressional Elections, 1975 Dec. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Heinz Eulau's Orientation and Research: A Study of the Behavioral Movement in Political Science, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Reader's Report, Gallant Gamble: Explorations in Legislative Behavior, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Syllabus, The Social Matrix of Political Behavior, 1960 Fall (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Syllabus, The Cultural Context of Political Behavior, 1960 Win. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Syllabus, The Cultural Context of Political Behavior, 1961 Win. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Syllabus, The Cultural Context of Political Behavior, 1959 Win. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Syllabus, The Social Matrix of Political Behavior, 1959 Fall (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Syllabus, Personality in Politics, 1960 Spr. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Syllabus, Personality in Politics, 1959 Spr. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Syllabus, Personality in Politics, 1961 Spr. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Syllabus, The Social Matrix of Political Behavior, 1958 Fall (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Syllabus, Introduction to the Study of Political Behavior, 1962 Fall (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Final Examination, American Government and Politics, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Books, Some Recent Pan Americana, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - The New Soviet Nationalism, 1944 Mar. (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Liberalism against populism: A confrontation between the theory of democracy and the theory of social choice, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Department of Political Science, Stanford University, 1920-1970 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Segments of Political Science Most Susceptible to Behavioristic Treatment, 1962 Oct. (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Standing Committees in Legislatures: Three Decades of Research, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - From Utopia to Probability: Liberalism and Recent Science, 1966 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - The Way It Was... 1937, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Introduction of Norman Nie at Biennial Meeting of the Inter-University Consortium for Political and Social Research, 1989 Nov. 11 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Values and Behavioral Science: Neutrality Revisited, 1968 Sum. (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Reasons and Relevance, Reflections on a Madness of Our Time, 1972 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Neither Ideology Nor Utopia: The New Deal in Retrospect, 1959-1960 Win. (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Religion and Power, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - The Chicago Jewish Forum, 1947 Sum. (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Asia and The Americas, 1946 Oct. (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Germany: Economic and Labour Conditions under Facism, Review, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - The International Quarterly, 1942 Spr. (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Some Critical Roles of American State Legislators: A Research Proposal, undated (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Book Department, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Legislative Progress, undated (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - The Limits of Behavioralism in Political Science, 1962 Oct. (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - Experimental Study of Politics, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - American Politlcal Science Review, undated (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Social Cleavages in the 1990s in Comparative Perspective: The Cross National Election Project, Review, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - Small Groups in Legislative Politics: A Potpurri of Comments on a Potpurri of Papers, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Three-Button Benny and Municipal Government, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - The Journal of Politics, 1942 Feb. (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - The Role of the Representative: Some Empirical Observatiosn on the Theory of Edmund Burke, undated (Box 23, Folder 56)
  - Canadian Journal of Political Science, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 57)
  - The Congress as Research Arena: An Uneasy Partnership between History and Political Science, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - Some Remarks on Comparative Analysis and the STudy of American State Politics, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - Some Further Observations on Some Problems and the Advantages of Comparative Cross-State Research, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 60)
  - Legislative Research in Historical Perspective, An Introduction, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 61)
  - Legislative Committes on Interstitial Structures in Constituency Representation: The Case of the American Congress, 1982 Oct. (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - Legislative Committee Assignment, 1984 Nov. (Box 23, Folder 63)
  - Adaption through Proliferation: Toward Understanding the Congressional Committe System in the Proliferating Society, 1981 Feb. (Box 23, Folder 64)
  - The New Democracy: Proliferation and the Institution Structure of Congressional Committee System, 1982 May (Box 23, Folder 65)
  - III: 10. Of Responsiveness, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - III: 10. Accent Responsiveness, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - 11. Responsibility, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - 12. Trust and Discretion, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - IV: 13 Stlye and Focus, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - IV: 14. Constituency Control and Style of Representation, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - IV. 15. Concurrence, Responsiveness, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - 16. Representation as Support vs. Demand, undated (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - V. Capabilities and Obstacles, undated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - 17. Citizens Capabilites, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - 18. Resillience and Affluence, undated (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - 19. Representation and Social Order: Power and Status, undated (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Representation Outlines, etc., 1981 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - 20. Of Mandate and Authorization, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - 22. Of Complexity and Vulnerability, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - 23. Diversity and Pluralism, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - VII. Social, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - 25. Of Observing and Measuring, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - 26. Of Direct and Surrogate Variables, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - 27. Cornelalion Coefficient, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - 28. Representation as Network: Direct and Indirect Communication, the Multiple Meanings of Linkage, undated (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Lyn Ragsdale, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - A Working Model for the Measurement of Tension in the Legislative System, 1956 Aug. 16 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - The Congruence Model Revisited: Converse and Pierce on Constituency Representation in France, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - X. Agenda for the Future, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Mansbridge, Adversaray Democracy, undated (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - The Neglected World of State Politics, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - The Study of Individual Legislators, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - The Evolution of the Property Tax: A Study of the Relation between Public Finance and Political Theory, undated (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Extensions, 1985 Fall (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam, Faculteit der Sociale Wetenschappen, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Learning from Recent Interviewing of Dutch MPs, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - The European Parliament: Political Influence is More than Legal Powers, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - American Politlcal Science Review, Manuscript Evaluation, undated (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - Structural Explanations of Turnout in the United States, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - Representative Democracy and Partisanship: An Application of a Pluralist Perspective to an Analysis of 30 Policy Issues in a Reformed Community, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - A Research Proposal for a Study of Representation, undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - News for Teachers of Political Science, 1983 Spr. (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Rights and Citizenship, undated (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Citizenship and Authority: A Chastened View of Citizenship, undated (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Kuklinski, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 41)
  - In Praise of the Legislative Way, undated (Box 24, Folder 42)
  - The Legislative Imperative: Building Broad-gauged Theory, 1983 Sep. 3 (Box 24, Folder 43)
  - Assorted Thoughts on the Study of Subgovernments, undated (Box 24, Folder 44)
  - Part Two: The Institution, 1981 (Box 24, Folder 45)
  - Comparison of the Function of Parliament in a Parliamentary System with the Function of Congress in a Presidential System, undated (Box 24, Folder 46)
  - The Contours and Complexity of Legislator Objectives: Empirically Examining the Basis of Purposive Models, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 47)
  - Purposive Roles of City Councilmen, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 48)
  - Role Orientations and the Prediction of Roll-Call Votes in a State Legislature: A Simulation, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 49)
  - Sources of Role Orientations: "Reality or Chance?", 1975 Nov. (Box 24, Folder 50)
  - The Legislative Role of Parliament in the British Political System, undated (Box 24, Folder 51)
  - The Role of Parliament in the Canadian Political System, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 52)
  - Comparative Legislative Research Center, 1973 Sep. (Box 24, Folder 53)
  - Corinne Silverman, Legislators' View of the Legislative Process, undated (Box 24, Folder 54)
  - Surburban Political Behavior: A Matter of Trust, 1974 Oct. (Box 24, Folder 55)
  - Toward a Theory of Legislative Behavior, 1962 Feb. 1 (Box 24, Folder 56)
  - The Institutionalization of Interests in Congress: An Organizational Perspective of Informal Groups, undated (Box 24, Folder 57)
  - American Political Science Review, Incumbent Candidacy, Success, and Turnover, undated (Box 24, Folder 58)
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation, 1982 Sep. 10 (Box 24, Folder 59)
  - Representation: News Clippings, undated (Box 24, Folder 60)
  - Parochialism of Congress Research, undated (Box 24, Folder 61)
  - Representation Clips, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 62)
  - Ratio Problem, Size of Assembly, Size of Constituency, undated (Box 24, Folder 63)
  - 21. Dyadic vs. Collective Representation, Fenno's Puzzle as MI-MA Problem, undated (Box 24, Folder 64)
  - Fables and Fancies on Academic Culture in the Study of Politics, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Harold Dwight Lasswell Society papers, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Electing the Senate Conference, 1989 Dec. 1-2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Electing the Senate Conference, papers, 1989 Dec. 1-2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - The Dilemma of Rational Legislative Action: Some Danish Evidence, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Will Democracy Kill Democracy? Decision-Making by Majorities and by Committees, 1975 Spr. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Preface, undated (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Representation, Introduction, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Outline, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Chapter III: 11, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Accountability and Incumbency, undated (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Florina on Collective Responsibility, undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Accountability, Responsiveness, Policy Agreement, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Accountability and Election, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Jewell notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Various accountability notes, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Decline of Collective Responsibility in American Politics, 1980 Apr. (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - American Journal of Political Science, Collective Representation Reappraised, undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Legislative Behavior: The Study of Representation, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Legislative Bibliographies, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Implementing Representation: A Framework and Two Applications, undated (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - 1. Classical Theory, undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - 2. The Study of Representation, undated (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - 3. The Democratic Bias, undated (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - 4. The Representation in the American Context, undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - Pitkin, undated (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - 5. Rebellious, Bonds, Linkages, undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - 6. Of Quotes, Symbolism, Legitimacy, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - 7. Constituency, "Who is Represented?", undated (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - 8. Desire and Interest, undated (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - III. Of Structures and Processes, undated (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - III. 9. Of Congruence, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - 10. Continuities and Alternatives, undated (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - Commitees - Legislative, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Commitees - Early Drafts, undated (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Committees: Update, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Commitees, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Representation, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Plagiarism, undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - International House - E38 Berkeley, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - E39, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Representation Papers, 1977-1978 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Representation Papers, 1980-1984 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - III. Theory and Method, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Behavior History, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - II. Reception, Diffusion and Survival, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Ch. 9 Of Cause, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - E30, undated (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Daedalus, 1997 Fall (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - American Politics, 1973 January (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Political Sceince in the United States of America, 1956 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Life Space and Social Networks as Political Contexts, 1986 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Social Science, 1976 Jun. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Easton, 1995 Jun. 14 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Face-to-Face Politics, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - I. Origins & Context, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Introduction, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Committee On Political Behavior 1949-1963, Committee on Governmental and Legal Processes, 1964-1972, 1973 Aug. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Assorted drafts, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Arrival and Departure: C. H., undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Easton Memoir. K. Monroe, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Ideas Defining a Free Society, 1997 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Introduction to the Policy Sciences: The Decision Process, Syllabus, 1997 Fall (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Breakthrough, 1951-1960 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Preface, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Outlines, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Outside Model: Foci of Representation, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - 5. The Inside Model, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - 4. Role Analysis & Behavior, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Toward the Federal Polity, 1973 Fall (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Assorted articles, searches, etc., undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Chapter A: Pontifex Maximus: The Manifold Credos of David Easton, or Two Revolutions that Never Were, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - David Easton and the Behavioralists, A Memoir on Revolutions, So-Called, in Political Science, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Temporal Order and Causal Inference, 1997 May (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - An organizational history of the intellectual origins of the American National Election Studies, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Voting Behavior, undated (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Being of the Establishment But Not in It, undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - The State of American Sociology, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Ch. 2 The Impact of the Behavioral Revolution, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Ch. 3 Understanding Political Life in America, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Ch. 24 On Models, Concepts and Projects in Voting Studies, undated (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Ch. 4 Political Science as Theatre and Reality, undated (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - II. Some Critical Perspective, undated (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Ch. 5 Social Science at the Crossroads, undated (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - III. Some Polemical Perspectives, undated (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Ch. 12 The Greening of Political Science, undated (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Ch. 13 Congress in a Democratic Perspective, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 35)
  - Ch. 14 Elite Analysis and Democratic Theory, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 36)